Bekir Uğur

Software Developer

As a +3 years Experienced Certified Software Developer, having the ability to learn quickly, attention to details, adaptation to teamwork and being self-motivated play an active role in projects. Offering combination of proven problem-solving, analytical thinking, adaptation and communication skills. Seeking to join a synergic and harmonious team as a Full Stack Developer to develop amazing applications.

Contact

E-mail : Konya / Turkey

Phone: +90 542 648 79 96

Email: bekirugur070@gmail.com

Github: www.github.com/bekirugurr

Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/bekirugurr/

Portfolio site: https://bekirugur.netlify.app/

Software

Frontend:

JavaScript | React.js | Redux HTML | CSS | Tailwind | Bootstrap | SASS | Material UI

Backend:

Python | Django | Restful APIs SQL | PostgreSQL | OOP

Others:

Git | Github | Linux Agile | Jira | SDLC

Want to Learn:

TypeScript | React Native Docker | AWS

Soft Skills

Communication | Collaboration
Teamwork | Responsibility
Adaptability | Empathy
Analytical Thinking
Problem Solving
Time Management
Lifelong Learning

Languages

Turkish (Native)
English (Advanced)

Experience

2021-10 - Trainee 2022-07 Clarusway - USA (Remote)

- Made designing, developing, debugging, testing, documenting and deploying. Used Agile methodologies (Scrum and Jira).
- Completed 20 middle-level and 1 capstone hands-on project.

2020-03 - Freelance Developer & Learner 2021-09 Remote

- Followed passion in a core of software development.
- Learned programming and developed functional and sustainable web applications with clean codes.
- Used HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Python.

Education

2021-09 - Full Stack Development Certificate Program 2022-07 Clarusway IT School - USA

- Successfully graduated after 9 months of intensive work. Attended 540 hours of in-class lessons.
 Completed 1000+ hours of pre-class and post-class activities.
- Completed 20 middle-level and 1 capstone hands-on project.

2008-09 - Public Administration (Bachelor's Degree)2012-06 Ankara University - Turkey

Certifications

2022-07 - Backend & Django Course Certificate (Clarusway)
 2022-05 - Frontend & React Course Certificate (Clarusway)
 2022-05 - HTML/CSS/Javascript Course Certificate (Clarusway)

Frontend Projects (For details please read my documentations on github readmes)

- React Blog App: It is aimed to create blog posts and display them on the dashboard. Adding, deleting and updating blog posts, register, login, logout and updating profile can be done. Both frontend (react) and backend (django rest framework) were made by me. Tools: Material-ui Library, Axios, Redux, React-router DOM, Formik and Yup Libraries, React-toastify Library, PostgreSQL, Heroku, Django.
- React Movie App: It displays film details, posters and fragmants by using the tmdb api. There is a search feature according to the entered word. In addition, Firebase was used for register, login and authentication. Context API was used. Tools: React-router library, Bootstrap library, Context API, Axios and Firebase
- React To Do App: User can add task with priority level and labels, mark tasks as completed or uncompleted and delete them. Comleted and uncompleted tasks look different. User can view all tasks, to-do tasks and done tasks separately. Tools: Tailwind, Rest API (mock api), axios, local storage.
- React Personal Portfolio: Fully responsive personel website. Framer Motion and react_scroll are used for animation and transition. Firebase realtime database was used for receiving messages. *Tools: React, Framer Motion, Tailwind, Firebase.*
- Checkout Page: A real e-commerce website's checkout page. There is a cart for buying products, and we can increase,
 decrease the number of products or remove the product. By changing a parameter in the cart, our js functions calculate
 the cart total price. Tools: DOM, Iterator, Callback functions, String-array functions and Events.
- Movie Ticket App: A website that sells event tickets. Users can view the events, available seats for the event, claim what they want among them and see the amount they will pay. *Tools: Json, Local Storage and Array Methods*.
- **los Calculator**: In this project, the goal is to make a functional and visual clone of the calculator of an iOS device. *Tools:* HTML, CSS Frameworks, JS Dom Manipulation and Event Listeners.
- Lottery Ticket App: An app that generates lottery tickets. User can get max 8 tickets at once. The first 6 numbers will be in ascending order and different from each other. The 7th (joker) number cannot be the same as the first 6 digits. The 8th (superstar) number can be any between 1 to 90. Tools: HTML, CSS, JS, Dom Manipulation and Event Listeners.
- Find The Number Game App: When this application is opened, it keeps a number between 1 and 100 and gives the user 7 rights to guess correctly. When user guesses wrong, application narrows range of numbers based on last guess and gives notifications about remaining rights. Tools: HTML, CSS, JS, Dom Manipulation and Event Listeners.

Backend Projects (For details please read my documentations on github readmes)

- **Django Blog API**: Backend side of blog app above. In this project adding, deleting and updating blog posts, register, login, logout and updating profile can be done. While in development process backend SQLite, in production process it is *PostgreSQL. Tools: Django Rest* Framework, *PostgreSQL, Concrete views, Viewsets, Token authentication, custom and object permissions, cursor pegination, dj rest auth, nested serializer,* select_related method, swagger, debug toolbar
- **Blog App With Django Templates**: In appearance similar to the above application. But in above app, react was used as frontend and django rest framework was used as backend for API. In this app, just django was used for both frontend and backend. Django templates works as frontend. *Tools: Bootstrap, Django, Django Templates, Crispy forms*
- To Do App With Django Templates: To do app using django as backend and django templates as frontend. Users can add, update, delete todos and can change as done or undo. Tools: Bootstrap, Django, Django Templates, Crispy forms
- **Django Quiz API**: Quiz API generates test quizzes. There are answers under questions under quizzes under categories. Admin panel was customized as nested admin panel so that the admin can enter the exam, questions and answers together. Adding, deleting and updating can be done. *Tools: Django Rest* Framework, *PostgreSQL, Concrete views, Token authentication, custom permissions, dj rest auth, nested serializer,* swagger, redoc, debug toolbar.
- **Flight Reservation API**: An API that allows create, update, delete or read flights, reservations and passengers in different ways according to whether user is staff or not. User can register, login, logout, update profile. *Tools: Django Rest* Framework, *PostgreSQL, Concrete views, Token authentication, custom permissions, dj rest auth, nested serializer,* swagger, redoc, debug toolbar.